<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drupal on Homesteading</title>
    <link>http://ebsen.me/categories/drupal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drupal on Homesteading</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ebsen.me/categories/drupal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Frosty Ticket 2.0</title>
      <link>http://ebsen.me/project/frosty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ebsen.me/project/frosty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the unit responsible for the university&amp;rsquo;s public web presence, we support about 200 other faculty and staff around campus who regularly edit CommonSpot (and soon, Drupal) or another of our websites in some way. We wanted a way track their requests, both to ensure the work got done but also to build data around how people were using our sites. What common problems did they experience? Where was our documentation failing them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a joke, an earlier version of this tool was temporarily dubbed &amp;ldquo;Frosty Ticket.&amp;rdquo; The name stuck, so when we decided to rebuild this system in Drupal, I knew we had to name it &lt;em&gt;Frosty Ticket 2.0&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its current state, Frosty Ticket 2.0 is a simple website. You log in, log the tasks you need to do, and mark them off as they&amp;rsquo;re completed. We can note which college or unit a request belongs or assign a task to another user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Boyd College Connection</title>
      <link>http://ebsen.me/project/west-boyd-college-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:56:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ebsen.me/project/west-boyd-college-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The West Boyd College Connection is a resource for students primarily in the Nebraska school district beginning their research into post-secondary education. In addition to information on college interviews, applications, and campus visits, the website features a fairly exhaustive catalog of area scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the school&amp;rsquo;s guidance counselor curates this list of scholarships by hand, sorting them by due date. March alone includes roughly a hundred entries. The website is not particularly friendly to mobile displays devices either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new Drupal version of the site, she&amp;rsquo;ll enter every scholarship exactly the same way. Drupal&amp;rsquo;s powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drupal.org/project/views&#34;&gt;Views&lt;/a&gt; module will do all the sorting and categorized display for her. Students with mobile devices will be able to use the site as effectively as those with a laptop or desktop computer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News Center</title>
      <link>http://ebsen.me/project/news-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 21:12:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ebsen.me/project/news-center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the time it launched, the News Center represented our team&amp;rsquo;s most significant Drupal website to date and served as a demonstration to the campus community how Drupal could transform how we publish content to the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a great deal of effort with this project to determine the needs of our news writers: what they wanted to accomplish from a news-publishing website, how their current tools were costing them time and effort, and what they wanted from an ideal setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Drupal&amp;rsquo;s flexibility, we were able to customize the editing experience to make publishing stories and images quicker and less error-prone for the writers. Drupal&amp;rsquo;s powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drupal.org/project/views&#34;&gt;Views&lt;/a&gt; module also let us customize the website&amp;rsquo;s output, allowing us to categorize stories and display them across the site according to features or magazines printed by the marketing department.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>