<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homesteading</title>
    <link>ebsen.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Homesteading</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 13:59:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="ebsen.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduating from College</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/post/graduating-from-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 13:59:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/post/graduating-from-college/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I expected that leaving &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdstate.edu&#34;&gt;someplace I&amp;rsquo;d worked for nearly eight years&lt;/a&gt; would involve more ceremony. It didn&amp;rsquo;t. I announced that I was leaving and two weeks later, I left. That was pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I programmed at State for years but I also wore a lot of other hats&amp;mdash;like providing technical support and content strategy to the university&amp;rsquo;s editors across campus&amp;mdash;and over time I realized that as much as I like coding and as much success as I think we found with that there, the university needed someone to continue wearing those hats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later this month I will start my new job as a programmer for &lt;a href=&#34;http://good-sam.com&#34;&gt;The Good Samaritan Society&lt;/a&gt;. Another team handles testing. Another team handles support. Since our team builds web apps rather than a single giant (largely informational) website, I won&amp;rsquo;t be dealing with content in the same way that I did at a large sprawling public university website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to join a larger team with other, more experienced developers with whom I can ask questions or compare thoughts. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to work with a team that does dedicated testing. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to hand off support duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to start building software again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Episodes I through III</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/post/rethinking-episodes-i-through-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 17:26:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/post/rethinking-episodes-i-through-iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Note: With The Force Awakens arriving on iTunes and video earlier this month and the trailer for this year&#39;s Rogue One dropping this week, I thought this made as good a time as any to dust off and finish a post I started around the time that The Force Awakens hit theaters in the US. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everyone else in the universe, I saw &lt;em&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/em&gt; over the holidays. The day after, I introduced my son (age six) to &lt;em&gt;Episode I: The Phantom Menace&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He loved it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, he loved most of all the parts that cause me and so much of the rest of the Internet to groan and sigh and wail: the perpetual, gratuitous fish-eating-fish in the center of the Naboo; that a boy (hardly older than him) might fly a ship into space and knock out an entire starship by accident; and, yes, Jar Jar Binks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, he loved all the accidents. He really enjoys physical comedy and, truthfully, The Phantom Menace deals that out in spades. He laughed at every clumsy droid antic. Jar Jar&amp;rsquo;s stupid stunts though really made him roll. The kid was jumping up and down in glee over all the things that make me cringe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since he really doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow dialogue, he completely missed everything about midi-chloridians. He missed a lot of things, really. He still absolutely loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard George Lucas defend the movies in general (and Jar Jar in particular) as &amp;ldquo;Well, kids enjoy it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That my son loved this movie didn&amp;rsquo;t really surprise me. What did surprise me was how much more &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; enjoyed the film watching it with him. Sure, he asked a thousand questions, sometimes all at once. The dialogue mostly bored him. (On that, we agree.) Still, seeing him genuinely crack up so hard over all the cheesy stuff caused me to lighten up a little about the while thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night, he brought his toy light saber to bed with him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Many Projects</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/post/so-many-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 11:28:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/post/so-many-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before relaunching it as what it is now, this site served as a portfolio of personal and professional projects. Today, I finally got around to porting (most) of those projects over to this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my personal favorites include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project/graduation-2015&#34;&gt;Graduation 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project/hobo-day-parade&#34;&gt;Hobo Day Parade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project/news-center&#34;&gt;News Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project/songbook&#34;&gt;Songbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- In addition to that, I finally corrected my long-standing error of not keeping this site under version control. While I struggle with how to represent everything that ebsen.me has contained, that&#39;s no reason not to track it _somehow_. --&gt;

&lt;!-- I had been dragging my feet on this because I couldn&#39;t decide between trying to self-host this site on a Raspberry Pi or just running it off GitHub Pages. Since my Pi just arrived yesterday, I&#39;ll need to play around with it for awhile before I make that decision. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project&#34;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; page for all the details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ag Museum</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/ag-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:59:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/ag-museum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A custom-themed WordPress site built from Photoshop designs. It features a prominent carousel on the homepage and several post types to display information in various places across the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led a team of myself and two student developers to prototype these designs into code. I chose &lt;a href=&#34;http://foundation.zurb.com/&#34;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; as the front-end framework and &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; to compile it. These technologies helped us built the site responsively, allowing it to work across difference screen sizes. We then converted the resulting code to work with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was our first project using responsive design and the above technologies. Today, every project we start is responsive, we have several sites running on WordPress, and we use Node with nearly every website we have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dice</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/dice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/dice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This project is deprecated in favor of &lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project/ranger&#34;&gt;Ranger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Fourth of July the family and I visited my parents. There, my mom keeps this huge Disney-themed book of board games. the games all use a digital built-in display instead of dice.  Only one problem: the batteries were dead and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any dice in the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I improvised by writing a very simple node script that returned a random number from one to six. Easy enough. Each played &amp;ldquo;rolled the dice&amp;rdquo; by tapping the Up key to bring up the previous command (this ad hoc dice script, in this case) and hit return to get a new number back. It worked for our game that afternoon (crisis averted!) but I can&amp;rsquo;t say the kids enjoyed it much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to simplify things for the next time this happens, I wrapped that little script in a web page. Now, instead of fiddling with an arcane command prompt to &amp;ldquo;roll&amp;rdquo; a digital die, you just click a button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon seeing the project, a friend (who may or may not play a little D&amp;amp;D) called me out for only supporting six-sided die. So I added a Settings pane to allow you to configure the number of imaginary sides on your imaginary die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, the singular of &amp;ldquo;dice&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;die.&amp;rdquo; I kept saying &amp;ldquo;dice&amp;rdquo; and my wife kept ruthlessly correcting my improper conjugation.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frosty Ticket 2.0</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/frosty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/frosty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the unit responsible for the university&amp;rsquo;s public web presence, we support about 200 other faculty and staff around campus who regularly edit CommonSpot (and soon, Drupal) or another of our websites in some way. We wanted a way track their requests, both to ensure the work got done but also to build data around how people were using our sites. What common problems did they experience? Where was our documentation failing them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a joke, an earlier version of this tool was temporarily dubbed &amp;ldquo;Frosty Ticket.&amp;rdquo; The name stuck, so when we decided to rebuild this system in Drupal, I knew we had to name it &lt;em&gt;Frosty Ticket 2.0&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its current state, Frosty Ticket 2.0 is a simple website. You log in, log the tasks you need to do, and mark them off as they&amp;rsquo;re completed. We can note which college or unit a request belongs or assign a task to another user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Time</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/gametime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/gametime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted a super-simple way to keep score at our son&amp;rsquo;s soccer games. The app has two buttons, one for each score. Tap to add a point. Refresh the page to reset both scores to zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the buttons easier to tap, I placed them especially large and near the bottom of the screen. To eliminate the tap delay on mobile browsers, I added &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftlabs.github.io/fastclick/&#34;&gt;FastClick&lt;/a&gt;. I also disabled page zooming and the bouncy-scroll thing that Safari does at the bottom of the page. In most cases, these UI features serve a purpose. In this case, they introduce complexity and make those two big obvious buttons just a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; harder to hit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation 2015</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/graduation-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/graduation-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An official university landing page to highlight the accomplishments of our graduating bachelors, masters, and Ph.D. students, including live streams of the commencement ceremonies over YouTube, &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VTRt64lE3uQ&#34;&gt;our own original recap video&lt;/a&gt;, and curated Instagram and Twitter posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our first experience at streaming live video, we needed a lean website that would perform really well. So we opted to go without a database and we optimized common performance bottlenecks to reduce the size of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also worked with IT to put together a new way for us to publish the website. This also allows us to much more easily track changes in the code and revert them when bugs are discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The live stream was a huge success for us, reaching hundreds of people across 26 states and 11 countries and reaching the highest number of mobile viewers (32%) of any university website to date. In the time since, the recap video has reached thousands of viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;//graduation.sdstate.edu&#34;&gt;current iteration of the graduation website&lt;/a&gt; adds &lt;a href=&#34;https://storify.com/SDState/sdstate15&#34;&gt;social media integration through Storify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/user/sdstate/playlist/2xNGtjV0ghaypMHwCmBwfv&#34;&gt;a music playlist from Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152904174661647.1073741842.88914146646&amp;amp;type=1&#34;&gt;a Facebook photo album&lt;/a&gt;. I also scripted our Git deployment process to make publishing and updating the site much simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building on success in our 2014, the website reached people in 43 states and 32 countries on commencement day. A strong majority of those visitors (57%) came from mobile, breaking our previous record. The Facebook photo album on the site reached over 100,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobo Day Parade</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/hobo-day-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:58:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/hobo-day-parade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The website for our first-ever live stream of the annual Hobo Day parade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built in just a few days, I used a number of new &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; tools. &lt;a href=&#34;http://harpjs.com/&#34;&gt;Harp&lt;/a&gt; produced a local copy of the website (written in two new languages, &lt;a href=&#34;http://jade-lang.com/&#34;&gt;Jade&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lesscss.org/&#34;&gt;Less&lt;/a&gt;) while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.browsersync.io/&#34;&gt;BrowserSync&lt;/a&gt; let me share that website live to the rest of the team while I worked. This project became the template we use to build the majority of static websites today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posts to social media in the weeks leading up to Hobo Day help to build a crescendo around the event and the website, leading to more people (62%) watching the parade&amp;rsquo;s live stream from the website than from YouTube itself. Nearly half of viewers (45%) did so from a mobile device, another record at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Video 2014</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/holiday-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:57:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/holiday-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of each year, the university publishes a video to highlight the accomplishments made by its faculty and staff. This year, that email campaign also kicked off #WeAreSDState, a campaign to promote the university&amp;rsquo;s value around the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted the website hosting the video to match the email used to distribute it. This led me to experiment with animating backgrounds and cross-fading images in the browser. While the final product didn&amp;rsquo;t ship with these features, they served as excellent reminders that &amp;ldquo;the web&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t the same across screens and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranger</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/ranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:57:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/ranger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time after building &lt;a href=&#34;ebsen.me/project/dice&#34;&gt;Dice&lt;/a&gt;, my wife asked if I could modify it to allow a wider range of possible numbers. So I forked Dice to create Ranger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranger started just to help her play Bingo with the kids but I hope to get back around it it and rebuild it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org&#34;&gt;Elm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Boyd College Connection</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/west-boyd-college-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:56:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/west-boyd-college-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The West Boyd College Connection is a resource for students primarily in the Nebraska school district beginning their research into post-secondary education. In addition to information on college interviews, applications, and campus visits, the website features a fairly exhaustive catalog of area scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the school&amp;rsquo;s guidance counselor curates this list of scholarships by hand, sorting them by due date. March alone includes roughly a hundred entries. The website is not particularly friendly to mobile displays devices either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new Drupal version of the site, she&amp;rsquo;ll enter every scholarship exactly the same way. Drupal&amp;rsquo;s powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drupal.org/project/views&#34;&gt;Views&lt;/a&gt; module will do all the sorting and categorized display for her. Students with mobile devices will be able to use the site as effectively as those with a laptop or desktop computer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Paper Scissors</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/project/rock-paper-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 10:54:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/project/rock-paper-scissors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rock, Paper, Scissors is a game many of us learn as children. I thought I could use it to learn more about event handlers and logic in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app waits for you to choose between rock, paper, or scissors. Once you do, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Events&#34;&gt;an event fires&lt;/a&gt;. That event keeps a note of what you selected, gets the computer to pick, and notifies you whether you won or lost. The event only starts the game and updates the screen with the result. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the game itself. For that, we look to the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model contains the all logic for the game. It knows that scissors beats paper, paper beats rock, and so forth. It knows what you selected (because the event shared that information) and it knows how to tell the computer to select either rock, paper, or scissors at random. It then compares those two selections, decides the winner, and gives that information back to the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event updates the page to tell you whether you won, lost, or tied, and goes back to waiting for another selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, programming even very simple logic like &amp;ldquo;rock beats scissors, scissors beats paper, etc&amp;rdquo; can be done in all sorts of ways. I chose to keep the user interface and the game&amp;rsquo;s logic very separate because I know and like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model%E2%80%93view%E2%80%93controller&#34;&gt;Model-View-Controller&lt;/a&gt; pattern used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/General/Conceptual/DevPedia-CocoaCore/MVC.html&#34;&gt;iOS programming&lt;/a&gt; and web frameworks like &lt;a href=&#34;http://backbonejs.org/&#34;&gt;Backbone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Gauges and Practical UX</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/post/fuel-gauges-and-practical-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 20:26:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/post/fuel-gauges-and-practical-ux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I leave the house in the morning with a quarter tank of gas or less in the car, I won&amp;rsquo;t make it home again that night before the low fuel light turns on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most fuel gauges, the one in my car is linear: with the quarter, half, and three-quarter markers equal distances from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think about it that way. When the fuel is mostly full, I don’t care. When the fuel is mostly empty, I care a lot. As the fuel decreases, the value I assign to it increases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until a few years ago, I drove a late-eighties BMW 3 series. Among its many wonders, this little car offered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=e30+fuel+gauge&#34;&gt;a logarithmic fuel gauge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas my current car’s fuel gauge hovers near full, wanders down to half, and then plummets to empty, my old bimmer’s gauge would drop far more steadily. Since the bottom half of the tank took up the majority of the gauge, I got the most accurate fuel information &lt;em&gt;when I needed it most&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe BMW eventually stopped doing this, so the marks on a modern 3 series gauge are spaced equally just like that of any other car. Still, I miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. This car’s gauge cluster also featured a needle for the current fuel economy directly below (opposite) the current speed. This let you immediately understand you fuel consumption as you accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling the Trigger</title>
      <link>/ebsen.me/post/pulling-the-trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ebsen.me/post/pulling-the-trigger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve owned this domain for quite awhile. Every few years, I rebuild the website here and then let it sit mostly dormant until whenever I get around to completely rebuilding it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing this entire time. I just haven&amp;rsquo;t been &lt;em&gt;publishing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here goes. With social media and the web in general increasingly corporate, tracked, and monetized, I like the idea of getting away from all that and owning my own words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t expect a return to the hey-day of blogging that existed before social media swallowed it. I can still cross-post what I write here onto Facebook or Twitter or LinkedIn or Medium or wherever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>